ifttt.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy policy for our Site and Service - IFTTT

As of July 20th, 2018

IFTTT Inc. ("IFTTT") takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the IFTTT website located at ifttt.com (the "Site") and the services offered by IFTTT (the Site, Mobile Apps, and services referred to as the "Service"). Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more about the ways in which IFTTT uses and protects your personal information. By using the Service you acknowledge and agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms, please do not use the Service or access our Site. 

The IFTTT Service is not intended for use by children. If you are under 18, you may use the Service only with involvement of a parent or guardian. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 16. If you are under 16, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 16 may have provided us personal information, please contact us at [privacy@ifttt.com](mailto:privacy@ifttt.com). 

###### Information We Collect Automatically

Browsing the Site does not require you to register for an account or provide any personal information to us. In general, IFTTT will gather some generic information automatically. This generic information may include the internet address assigned to your computer, the number and frequency of visitors to the Site, the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on the Site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on the Site or not), and your computer browser information. Generic information does not reveal the identity of the visitor. This type of aggregate data may enable us to figure out how often users use parts of the Service, help us determine customer service and Site needs, and do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve you and our community. IFTTT may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. As part of this use of information, we may provide aggregate information, not information about you personally, to our partners about how our users, collectively, use our Service. 

We use analytics to help analyze how our users use the Services. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect information such as how often our users visit the Services, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Services. We may use the information we get from Google Analytics to improve our Services or to send you promotional messages about our Services. Google Analytics collects the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Services, but not your name or other personally identifying information. We do not combine the information generated through the use of Google Analytics with any personally identifying information. Although Google Analytics plants a persistent Cookie to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the Service, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Service is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You may find additional information about Google Analytics at [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). 

###### Information Collected From Other Websites and Do Not Track Policy

Through cookies we place on your browser or device, we may collect information about your online activity after you leave our Service. Just like any other usage information we collect, this information allows us to improve the Service and customize your online experience, and otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy. Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. Our Service does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we collect information about your online activity both while you are using the Service and after you leave our Service. 

###### Information You Provide to Us

We receive and store any information you enter on the Service or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, though you may not be able to take advantage of many Service features. The personal information you provide may be used for such purposes as responding to your questions or requests, customizing the content you see, and communicating with you about new Service features. If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Service, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. You agree that we may use your personal information to contact you as provided herein, though our intent is that email is the only channel we will use to contact you without your consent. 

Also, once you install any Mobile Apps and enable specific Platform Services, you may be providing us with additional information, such as contacts and camera-photos on your device. Additionally, we may collect information about your location and calendar in order to provide you with more personalized Service. Again, you can choose not to provide us with certain information, though you may not be able to take advantage of many Service features. 

If you provide your third-party account credentials to us or otherwise sign in to the Services through a third party site or Platform Service, you understand some content and/or information in those accounts (“Third Party Account Information”) may be transmitted into your account with us if you authorize such transmissions, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Services is covered by this Privacy Policy. 

One such service may include the ability for you to automatically transmit Third Party Account Information to your Services profile or to automatically transmit information in your Services profile to your third party account. 

In order for you to take full advantage of the Service, you must provide registration information, including an e-mail address and password. We may also request demographic information and unique identifiers in order to provide you with a more personalized service, but this information is optional. Once you register for the Service, create Applets, and/or give us your personal information, you are not anonymous to us. Usernames and links to public accounts are only shown on your profile with your consent. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to register for the Service or create any Applets. Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, and efficient experience. We only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose. IFTTT does not sell or rent your personal information to third parties without your explicit consent. IFTTT may disclose information it has collected from you and/or that you have made available through the Service when it believes in good faith that the law or legal process requires it, or when it is necessary to do so to protect the rights or property of IFTTT or others. You are responsible for managing the flow of your private information from one third party Platform Service to another. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, that information becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others and redistributed through the internet and other media channels. For example, if you push a private post on Facebook to a public blog, the private post will no longer be private. You may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

###### Is My Information Secure?

We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We use industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software to protect the security of your personal information during transmission, which encrypts all of the information you input. All personal information collected from other Platform Services that you provide through the use of the Service is stored securely. Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices. 

Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example, we may be forced to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. 

You need to work to protect against unauthorized access to your passwords and to your computer by signing off once you have finished using a shared computer. You are responsible for all actions taken with your User ID and password. Therefore we recommend that you do not disclose your password to any third parties. If you choose to share your User ID and password or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken with your account and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf such as if someone used your User and ID password to forward libelous material through the Service. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password. 

###### What about Cookies?

When you visit the Site, we may send one or more "cookies" to your computer hard drive through your Web browser. A cookie is a small file containing a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Any use of cookies by us will be solely for the purposes of improving the quality of access to the Site by storing user preferences, and tracking user trends, such as how people use the Site, and their Site access preferences. Cookies tell us how and when pages in our Site are visited and by how many people. We use cookies to allow you to enter your login information less frequently. To the extent IFTTT uses cookies, such cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your username or e-mail address is. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Site and you may be required to reenter your password or login information more frequently. IFTTT visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the Site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. We recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because deleting cookies may reduce the functionality of IFTTT. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. 

###### Will IFTTT Share Any of the Information it Receives with Other Entities?

We may use third party service providers to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of our business and therefore we may provide some of your personal information directly to these service providers. These service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information we provide them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced IFTTT related operation, unless you have given your prior permission to them for additional uses. We may share our data, including personal information about you with our partners and joint ventures in furtherance of our business. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. Our partners and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this document, to the extent allowed by applicable law. In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. 

Moreover, if IFTTT, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that IFTTT goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, customer information would be one of the assets that may be transferred to or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of IFTTT may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy. IFTTT cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws and intellectual property rights. Therefore, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, city, state, telephone number, and email address. We will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other government officials without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or report suspected illegal activity. This Privacy Policy applies to the IFTTT Service only. We do not exercise control over any sites that you may visit from a link on our Site. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Since IFTTT does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy policies of that third party. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. 

We may de-identify your Personal Information so that you are not identified as an individual, and provide that information to our partners. We may also provide aggregate usage information to our partners (or allow partners to collect that information from you), who may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Services, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal online experience. However, we never disclose aggregate usage or de-identified information to a partner (or allow a partner to collect such information) in a manner that would identify you as an individual person. 

Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your personal information may be shared with third parties, and you will be able to prevent the sharing of this information. 

###### Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information

Services can be disconnected at anytime though prior Applets may remain in our electronic archive. You can change your email address and contact information by going to the settings page. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. You may be able to add or update certain additional information via the Service. When you update information, however, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. Please note that information may remain in our records after deletion of your account. IFTTT will only update your information on third party sites or send you information (phone, sms, etc.) with your specific consent, such as when you add Applets to your account. 

###### User Communications

You may input your contact information into the Service so that IFTTT may contact you. When you enter your contact information or send an email or other communication to IFTTT, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries and respond to your requests. We do not use your email address or contact information to send commercial or marketing messages nor do we give or sell this information to any third parties. To the extent your e-mail address is provided to IFTTT, you may receive e-mail or other communications from us. 

###### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: [privacy@ifttt.com](mailto:privacy@ifttt.com) or IFTTT Inc., 923 Market Street STE 400, San Francisco, California, 94103, Attn: Legal 

###### Changes to this Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Policy changes on this page. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amend terms on the Site. All amended terms shall automatically be effective thirty (30) days after they are initially posted on the Site. Each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date. 

###### Contact Us

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this policy or the Service in general, please feel free to contact us at [privacy@ifttt.com](mailto:privacy@ifttt.com). 

If you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”), United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, or Iceland, you may have additional rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) with respect to your Personal Data, as outlined below. 

For this section, we use the terms “Personal Data” and “processing” as they are defined in the GDPR, but “Personal Data” generally means information that can be used to individually identify a person, and “processing” generally covers actions that can be performed in connection with data such as collection, use, storage and disclosure. IFTTT will be the controller of your Personal Data processed in connection with the Service. 

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy, the policy or portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following applies to you, please contact us at [IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com](mailto:IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com). 

###### What Personal Data Do We Collect From You?

We collect Personal Data about you when you provide such information directly to us, when third parties such as our business partners or service providers provide us with Personal Data about you, or when Personal Data about you is automatically collected in connection with your use of our Service. 

Information we receive directly from you: We receive Personal Data directly from you when you provide us with such Personal Data, including without limitation the following: 

  * First and last name
  * Email address
  * Mailing address
  * Telephone number
  * Transaction Information (IFTTT does not store your credit or debit card information)
  * User content, for example, action ingredients that are displayed when an Applet runs

Information we receive from third party sources includes Applet trigger fields, ingredients, and action fields. This data is unique to your use of IFTTT and can be found on the Applet configuration panel for any of your Applets: <https://ifttt.com/my_applets>. 

Some third parties, such as our business partners and service providers, provide us with Personal Data about you, such as the following: 

  * Account information for third party Platform Services: If you interact with a third party Platform Service when using our Service, such as if you use a third party service to log-in to our Service (e.g., Facebook Login or Google Sign-In), or if you share content from our Service through a third party social media Platform Service, the third party service will send us information about you, such as information from your public profile, if the third party service and your account settings allow such sharing. The information we receive will depend on the policies and your account settings with the third party service. 
  * Information from our advertising partners: We receive information about you from some of our service providers who assist us with marketing or promotional services related to how you interact with our websites, applications, products, services, advertisements or communications. 
  * Information we automatically collect when you use our Service: Some Personal Data is automatically collected when you use our Service, such as the following: 
    * IP address
    * Device identifiers
    * Web browser information
    * Page view statistics
    * Browsing history
    * Usage information
    * Transaction information (e.g. transaction amount, date and time such transaction occurred)
    * Cookies and other tracking technologies (e.g. web beacons, pixel tags, SDKs, etc.)
    * Location information (e.g. IP address, zip code)
    * Log data (e.g. access times, hardware and software information)

###### How Do We Use Your Personal Data?

We process Personal Data to operate, improve, understand and personalize our Service. For example, we use Personal Data to: 

  * Create and manage user profiles
  * Communicate with you about the Service
  * Process orders
  * Contact you about Service announcements, updates or offers
  * Provide support and assistance for the Service
  * Personalize website content and communications based on your preferences
  * Meet contract or legal obligations
  * Respond to user inquiries
  * Fulfill user requests
  * Comply with our legal or contractual obligations
  * Resolve disputes
  * Protect against or deter fraudulent, illegal or harmful actions
  * Enforce our Terms of Service

We will only process your Personal Data if we have a lawful basis for doing so. Lawful bases for processing include consent, contractual necessity and our “legitimate interests” or the legitimate interest of others, as further described below. 

  * Contractual Necessity: We process the following categories of Personal Data as a matter of “contractual necessity”, meaning that we need to process the data to perform under our Terms of Use with you, which enables us to provide you with the Service. When we process data due to contractual necessity, failure to provide such Personal Data will result in your inability to use some or all portions of the Service that require such data. 
  * Legitimate Interest: We process the following categories of Personal Data when we believe it furthers the legitimate interest of us or third parties. Examples of these legitimate interests include: 
    * Operation and improvement of our business, products and services
    * Marketing of our products and services
    * Provision of customer support
    * Protection from fraud or security threats
    * Compliance with legal obligations
    * Completion of corporate transactions

  * Consent: In some cases, we process Personal Data based on the consent you expressly grant to us at the time we collect such data. When we process Personal Data based on your consent, it will be expressly indicated to you at the point and time of collection. 

  * Other Processing Grounds: From time to time we may also need to process Personal Data to comply with a legal obligation, if it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or other data subjects, or if it is necessary for a task carried out in the public interest. 

###### How and With Whom Do We Share Your Data?

We share Personal Data with vendors, third party service providers and agents who work on our behalf and provide us with services related to the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Service. These parties include: 

  * Payment processors
  * Fraud prevention service providers
  * Ad networks
  * Analytics service providers
  * Staff augmentation and contract personnel
  * Hosting service providers
  * Co-location service providers
  * Telecommunications service providers

We also share Personal Data when necessary to complete a transaction initiated or authorized by you or provide you with a product or service you have requested. In addition to those set forth above, these parties also include: 

  * Other users (where you post information publicly or as otherwise necessary to effect a transaction initiated or authorized by you through the Service) 
  * Social media services (if you interact with them through your use of the Service)
  * Third party business partners who you access through the Service
  * Other parties authorized by you

We also share Personal Data when we believe it is necessary to: 

  * Comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies
  * Maintain the security of our products and services

We also share information with third parties when you give us consent to do so. 

Last, we share Personal Data with our affiliates or other members of our corporate family. Furthermore, if we choose to buy or sell assets, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party, and we would share Personal Data with the party that is acquiring our assets. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy. 

###### How Long Do We Retain Your Personal Data?

We retain Personal Data about you for as long as you have an open account with us or as otherwise necessary to provide you Service. In some cases we retain Personal Data for longer, if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. Afterwards, we retain some information in a depersonalized or aggregated form but not in a way that would identify you personally. 

###### What Security Measures Do We Use?

We seek to protect Personal Data using appropriate technical and organizational measures based on the type of Personal Data and applicable processing activity. 

Personal Data of Children: We do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Data from anyone under the age of 16. If you are under 16, please do not attempt to register for the Service or send any Personal Data about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from a child under age 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 16 may have provided us Personal Data, please contact us at [IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com](mailto:IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com). 

###### What Rights Do You Have Regarding Your Personal Data?

You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Data, including those set forth below. For more information about these rights, or to submit a request, please email [IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com](mailto:IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com). Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your request, such as if it is frivolous or extremely impractical, if it jeopardizes the rights of others, or if it is not required by law, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision. In some cases, we may also need to you to provide us with additional information, which may include Personal Data, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request. 

  * Access: You can request more information about the Personal Data we hold about you and request a copy of such Personal Data. You can also access certain of your Personal Data by choosing to [export your data](https://ifttt.com/settings#control-your-data). 
  * Rectification: If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You can also correct some of this information directly by editing your [Account Settings](https://ifttt.com/settings). You can correct some of this information directly by editing your [Applets](https://ifttt.com/my_applets) or [Platform Services](https://ifttt.com/my_services). 
  * Erasure: You can [request that we erase](https://ifttt.com/settings#control-your-data) some or all of your Personal Data from our systems. 
  * Withdrawal of Consent: If we are processing your Personal Data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Service. 
  * Portability: You can [ask for a copy](https://ifttt.com/settings#control-your-data) of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format. You can also request that we transmit the data to another controller where technically feasible. 
  * Objection: You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your Personal Data for certain purposes, such as for direct marketing purposes. 
  * Restriction of Processing: You can ask us to restrict further processing of your Personal Data. 
  * Right to File Complaint: You have the right to lodge a complaint about IFTTT’s practices with respect to your Personal Data with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State. 
  * Transfers of Personal Data: The Service is hosted and operated in the United States (“U.S.”) through IFTTT and its service providers, and if you do not reside in the U.S., laws in the U.S. may differ from the laws where you reside. By using the Service, you acknowledge that any Personal Data about you, regardless of whether provided by you or obtained from a third party, is being provided to IFTTT in the U.S. and will be hosted on U.S. servers, and you authorize IFTTT to transfer, store and process your information to and in the U.S., and possibly other countries. 

###### What If You Have Questions Regarding Your Personal Data?

If you have any questions about this section or our data practices generally, please contact us using the following information: 

**Name:** IFTTT, Inc.  
**Physical address:** 923 Market Street, Suite #400, San Francisco, CA 94103  
  
**Designated representative and contact information:**   
DP-Dock GmbH  
Ballindamm 39  
20095 Hamburg

**Email:** [IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com](mailto:IFTTT@gdpr-rep.com)   
**Tel:** +49 (0) 40 99999 - 3430   
**Fax:** +49 (0) 40 99999 - 3332
